

Hung Pin Hsiao

Taipei, Taiwan muzicbee@gmail.com +886-920-997068

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Hi. I am Hung-Pin, a senior designer with sixteen years of UI design and frontend work experience. I have practical experience in product strategy thinking, user research, UI design, front-end and back-end implementation, and data tracking applications.

In addition to being the head of the design department (UI/UX, front-end), I am currently also serving as the Business Unit Head in a company. I mainly develop realtor technology applications.

I am full of interest and enthusiasm for user-centered research and exploring product possibilities, and I aim to deliver the value brought by the product goal to users without loss.

By the way, I'm a super fan of indie music:D!

EDUCATION

2009-2011

Chaoyang University of Technology Department of Applied Foreign

1996-2002

National Yunlin Institute of Technology Material Science

LANGUAGE

CHINESE

Mother Language

ENGLISH

Upper-intermediate

TOOLS

Photoshop / illurastor

Sketch / Figma

Miro

VScode / Git / Vue / Gulp

Kanboard / Trello

CERTIFICATE

Google UX Design Certificate

EXPERIENCE

Rakuya International Info. Co. Ltd | Chief Of Experience

2011/04 - Present

https://www.rakuva.com.tw

Supervisor of Design Department 2011 - 2013

Graphic Design

Leading graphic design work for bus advertisements/magazines/printed material/media.

Build a corporate identity system

Establish corporate identity, extending from graphic, media, to UI components.

Let the corporate image be able to establish a high degree of brand recognition and differentiation from competing products from marketing to user interface.

Manager of Design Department 2013 - 2016

APP / Responsive Web UI Lead

Leading APP and responsive website UI Design.

Frontend developing structure

Gulp frontend automation development / Git version controll

Senior Manager of Design Department 2016 - 2020

Build UI components & CSS/SCSS Framework

Based on corporate identity specifications and user feedback. Construct the application of the company's UI visual components (Sketch/Figma) and front-end components (Vue), so that users can have a more consistent experience when using services and improve system performance.

Chief of Product Experience/ Director 2020 - Present

UX Research and experience management

Lead colleagues to conduct Insight mining such as Case Study, Competitive Product Analysis, User Interview (Persona), Usability Test, Customer Journey Map, and Hotjar Website Hotspot Analysis.

Realtor Tech BU Lead

Formulate product strategies, instigate development, and plan annual operations.

YES123 | Web Designer

2007/07 - 2011/04

https://www.yes123.com.tw

- Website design
- Lead website structure form table to HTML5 DIV structure revision
- Event website / Flash game production
- · career expo lead designer / layout planning / exhibition output

PChome Online | Web Designer

2006/05 - 2007/05

http://www.pchome.com.tw

- \bullet Event webpage design, edms and ADs.
- Portal website design. (Skype and IPEVO)
- Graphic design (magazine, DM, advertising light box, etc)